You know, a lot of people I interview have had fleeting interactions in one-off instances.
You know, they've been abducted by a gray or they've, you know, interacted with a tall white or a Nordic.
You've had years of interactions with all three, but mostly with the tall whites.
There was this giant white radioactive horse that floated around the ranges at night and was fluorescent.
The extraterrestrials, when they come, even if they're your good friends, there's always a tension because they always come heavily armed.
Today's amazing guest on American Alchemy has seen the inside of a UFO.
He's a firsthand witness to the collaboration between human beings and aliens from another world.
He's even made an alien laugh.
Charles Hall was in the Air Force.
He was also stationed.
And at the notorious Area 51.
While stationed there, he was in regular contact with an alien race that he calls the tall whites for two years.
This conversation is absolutely wild.
There's a guy at NASA who has a deep interest in these sorts of things, experiencers.
His name is Timothy Taylor.
Have you heard of him by any chance?
Did you say Timothy Taylor?
Yeah.
He's a good friend of ours.
We're going to be talking about aliens going to the bathroom.
What powers?
A UFO and theories of subatomic physics that overturn Einstein.
Before we get into it, I want to introduce our guest, Charles Hall.
Hall enlisted in the US Air Force in 1964 when he was just 19 years old.
He trained as a weather observer, measuring wind speeds, cloud cover and visibility from 1965 to 1967.
He was stationed at Nellis Air Force Base in Nevada.
His job included long, isolated tours at the Indian Springs.
He was also a pilot for the American Air Force.
He flew to the American Air Force Base in 2006 to fly to Los Angeles.
TheFNDC.com has the story of Charles Hall.
I'm Charles Hall and this is the Italian host from the American Air Force.
Thanks for joining us on In This Minute.
If you're watching this video, be sure to subscribe, like, and turn on the bell.
And like this video, give it a thumbs up and make sure that you join our Discord group.
Share this video with a friend in your community.
We can't wait to hear your feedback and see some of your favorites.
We'll take a quick look at some of the most famous and most interesting facts that
are based around the American Air Force.
At first, he thought they were ghosts, or maybe hallucinations brought on by solitude.
Other observers had similar experiences.
They called it the legend of Range 4 Harry, a ghostly radioactive horse roaming the desert.
One observer was even injured in an encounter with something and given a medical discharge.
Others flat out refused to return to the post.
But Hall was very different.
Something about who he was meant that he wasn't going to break like the others had,
and both his commanders and these tall white beings seemed to take notice.
In this isolated crucible, he began slowly interacting with the tall whites.
These beings would stalk him and test him, appear suddenly and vanish, slowly gauging his reactions.
But he eventually learned this unwritten language.
And although there were some painful setbacks, he gradually developed a trust.
He saw family groups, parents, children, elders.
He would even end up referring to one of them as something like a brother.
Hall claims that the tall whites lived in underground facilities at the north end of Indian Springs Valley,
complete with hangers for their craft.
A story bearing striking resemblance to that of Bob Lazar.
He learned about their different flying crafts.
And as you'll see in our conversation, what he saw comports with much of what we've learned about UAPs since 2017.
But the tall whites were not the only ones.
They were the only alien race described in this story.
Hall has talked about the Greys, the small, frail, large-headed humanoids that matched the classic Roswell image.
The tall white technology was better than the technology of the Greys.
But the Greys come from a planet that's closer than the planet the tall whites come from.
And the Greys got here first.
And then there are the Nordics, what you'll hear Hall refer to as the Norwegians with the 24 T's.
Hall described them as more patient, more diplomatic, even benevolent compared to the tall whites.
Some of them could pass among humans in the public, sometimes blending into crowds.
There is no end to the speculation about how these alien species, who Hall suggests have been here for thousands of years,
might have interacted with humanity's evolution or social development.
If all of this sounds crazy, well, yeah, I don't blame you.
And trust me, we've only scratched the surface here.
I personally don't even know what to make about this conversation.
There are things Charles Hall is about to say that feel beyond the pale to me.
So that's my primer for you.
Without further ado, please welcome this week's amazing American alchemist, Charles Hall.
Today's episode is sponsored by Incogni.
Before we dive into today's episode of American Alchemy, I want to give a quick shout out to our amazing sponsor, Incogni.
This is a service that I use to make all of my personal information available.
A service that I use to make all of my personal information available.
To help you protect yourself against the virus, Incogni is都 codesu.com online.
Here's a fun, but slightly terrifying experiment.
Google your full name plus your city.
What comes up?
Old addresses, Family members, Court Records you didn't even know were public.
And maybe some bizarre risk profile that makes you sound like a Bond villain.
That's all thanks to Data Brokers, companies you've never heard of.
Quietly buying, selling and reselling your personal information to advertisers.
Political campaigns.
insurers, even scammers.
Incogni fights them for you.
They contact over 250 data brokers, they demand your data to be deleted and follow up until
it's actually gone.
And now they've launched something called custom removals, part of their unlimited plan.
Here's the upgrade.
If you find your information on any site anywhere on the internet, even ones outside of their
automated system, you just paste the link into your dashboard and Incogni's privacy
team will personally get it taken down and you get unlimited requests.
Think sites like whitepages.com, trellis.law, or unicort.com, places you'd never visit,
but where your data somehow lives rent free.
I personally use it because I don't have the time or quite frankly, the patience to chase
down every obscure website that's selling my address for $2 and 50 cents.
And with Incogni, I don't have to.
So take your personal data back with Incogni.
Use code.
American alchemy or go to incogni.com slash American alchemy to get 60% off an annual
plan.
Again, that is 60% off an annual plan.
That's over half the normal price off.
Online privacy isn't about paranoia.
It's about control.
And this is one of the easiest ways to get some of that control back.
So don't put it off.
Take care of your internet hygiene.
Now let's get back into this crazy episode.
I'm here with Charles Hall.
It's an honor to have you.
It's been a long time coming.
You're the subject of an amazing documentary by Emil Marczak called Walking with the Tall
Whites.
But you've also written a series of amazing books called Millennial Hospitality.
You have six volumes.
There's six volumes.
You have six volumes at this point.
And you've interacted with, you know, a lot of people I interview have had fleeting interactions
in one-off instances.
You know, they've been abducted by a gray or they've, you know, interacted with a tall
white or a Nordic.
You've had years.
You've had years of interactions with all three, but mostly with the tall whites.
And I really want to dive into that.
But first, I want to talk about your Hall photon theory.
You believe that Einstein is wrong and has limited physics, stagnated it for the last
century.
And so let's get into that.
I'm quite certain Einstein was wrong, though, and I've also written books entitled Beyond
Relativity.
And I've done a Rumble video entitled Mirage Galaxies and Edges in Space.
Edges is spelled with capital letters because it's a zone.
And I've also done a second film with Emil Marczak, which discusses that, called Walking
with the Tall Whites Aftermath.
And I've also...
That's all copyrighted.
Copyrighted Hall photon theory.
I first copyrighted Hall photon theory in 1997.
And I'm quite certain that there are many more particles, subatomic particles, and many
more types of force fields which exist in the real world.
And that's why relativity is not correct, because relativity doesn't take those into
account.
And for context for the audience.
Yeah.
You are extremely smart.
You have a master's degree in nuclear physics.
And you scored off the charts on one of these math tests before joining the Army.
And so...
I was in the Air Force.
And what you say is correct.
I got one wrong out of 500 on the Air Force math ability test.
It was the one I was marking as I was marking the correct answer as the clock had sounded
and they were ripping the answer sheet from my cold hands.
If they'd just given me 10 more seconds, I'd have got them all.
That's amazing.
But you told me off air that what inspired this Hall photon theory was you actually seeing
a craft and realizing it could go faster than light.
So you were stationed at Area 51.
That's correct.
I was a weather observer in the U.S. Air Force, and I was stationed at Nellis Air Force Base
from March of 1965 until May of 1970.
I was stationed at Nellis Air Force Base from March of 1965 until May of 1970.
That's correct.
I was stationed at Nellis Air Force Base from March of 1967.
And Nellis is in charge of the gunnery ranges at Indian Springs, and I was a duty weather
observer at Indian Springs.
Area 51 in 1965 was just the entry area to the areas, and the areas went up to number
60, and I've been in all of them.
The areas were assembled into lands.
One was the most famous land.
It was Dreamland.
Area 51 was not actually Dreamland itself.
It was merely Groom Lake.
Dreamland was Area 53 and 54, which was the northern half of Indian Springs Valley, and
then the valley to the east, Dogbone Valley, and part of the valley to the west, including
French Peak.
The biggest shock was not that extraterrestrials were here on Earth.
They were here on Earth.
And had been ever since at least the Ice Age.
The biggest shock that I felt was discovering that Einstein was wrong about relativity.
The craft that the tall whites and the greys came in, the Roswell greys came in, could
easily exceed the speed of light by many times.
The tall white technology was better than the technology of the greys.
But the greys come from a planet that's closer than the planet the tall whites come from,
and the greys got here first.
So I would guess that 90% of the time that you see an actual extraterrestrial craft,
it's one of the grey craft, and about 10% of the time it's one of the tall white craft.
And the greys are much more numerous for that reason.
So I would guess that 90% of the time, you see an actual extraterrestrial craft, it's
one of the grey craft.
And I remember the shock when I really, truly understood that Einstein was wrong about relativity.
I was out at Range 3 as the duty weather observer.
What year is this?
And this was in the mid-1960s.
This was like in 1965, the late summer.
And there was a six-week or two-month period where I was certain that the tall white individuals,
who identified themselves as the teacher, and Range 4 Harry, and tour guide, who were
my good friends, that they had taken a vacation or a business trip somewhere, and that they
weren't on this planet, and that they had gone to some other inhabited planet orbiting
some other star.
A reasonable guess would have been the star Arcturus, or a star near Arcturus.
And I remember thinking to myself, well, what's going on here?
Then they came back.
I believe they'd been on a business trip slash vacation-type trip.
Now, Arcturus is 36 light-years away, and the nearest star, Alpha Centauri, is almost
four light-years away.
It's a group of three stars.
And to go anywhere and come back to another star, the craft you were on had to travel
quite a few times faster than the speed of light.
Like, 44 times or something minimum, just to go there and come back in two months.
I think a lot of people in the audience might hear that they're coming back and forth
from a star system that is 36 light-years away, and want to know some core details as
to what you are seeing.
Do you see crafts coming in, and what do the crafts look like?
On schedule, on the night of the full moon, or a few days before, or a few days
after.
Their base at the north end of Indian Springs, they were using Dogbone Lake as their landing
field.
What do the crafts look like?
Like tic-tacs.
Yeah, like eggs, like white eggs.
They were egg-shaped.
Are they of the kind of, you know, David Fravor, 2004, the Nimitz sighting, where
you have a tic-tac?
Or was it like the egg that Jake Barber or, you know, Socorro knew Mexico?
64?
You know, those are two different, or both, both shapes.
When I first saw them, it reminded me the most of like a large version of a, of
the engine of a passenger train, only with, with everything rounded like an egg.
There were no sharp edges, no sharp protrusions, just smooth and round, like a round, it was
ellipsoidal.
Okay.
Any hieroglyphics or symbols?
Not in the outside.
When you went on, their writing is hieroglyphics, more so.
Their writing, if you didn't know Egyptian hieroglyphics, some, a couple of the guys that
were with me who had seen them thought that they were ancient Egyptians who had somehow
or another gotten into Indian Springs Valley and trapped there, and were still using their
own hieroglyphics.
Who thought that?
Oh, excuse me.
Yeah.
A couple of the other range men, yeah.
Interesting.
And they can stand right there in front of you, I speak from direct experience.
And if they feel like talking to each other using sounds too high for a human to hear,
they'll do so.
And if you didn't know better, you'd think they were able to do telepathy, because they'll
be sitting there in total silence and want to laugh, and then they'll be going through
a complete conversation.
And of course, their electronics also are able.
To tell what a person is thinking and to put thoughts in the conscious part of their
mind by electronic means.
Why do you think that?
From direct experience.
Did they have a device that could implant thoughts?
Yeah.
Only it wasn't a big device that they had to carry in their hands.
It was one that they'd carry like on a helmet or whatever.
And what's the broader context here?
Are you sort of this rogue Air Force range men, or do the other range men and superiors,
are they aware of this ET presence coexisting alongside you guys at this testing complex?
And is it sort of a, there's just this kind of awareness that there's this cohabitation
there?
The Pentagon had a tiny handful of people that knew their, that, you know,
interacted with them.
The range maintenance men, a few knew they were there, but most of them just knew about
the legend of range four Harry.
The range, the legend of range four Harry was that there was this giant white radioactive
horse that floated around the ranges at night and was fluorescent and supposedly was a horse
that had gotten too close to the bomb blasts at Yucca Plats.
And you'd see him on warm summer nights from a distance, and you could stay, but you needed
to stay away from him.
And he was called range four Harry.
Now there was an actual tall white guy with the name range four Harry.
And the tall whites, when they were wearing their protective suits, could form up into
a high speed horse force.
And it was a horse formation, like if there were a typical one, as if there were two women,
a couple, three kids, children, and two men, the two women would be in front and bend over
on that the waist and bend forward and put their arms out like that.
Some usually, and they would be the front of the horse.
And then the three children would, who's the remember their suits.
the technology of them allowed them to float
nine or ten inches off the ground.
They could float a lot higher if they wanted to,
but they had to balance themselves.
And the children would float,
whose suits were a slightly different design,
would float higher so that they were floating
at about the waist level.
So you'd have the two women in front
and the three children.
Then at the back, you'd have the two men
who had bigger suits and more powerful packs
and they would bend over the children.
So if you saw them when they were out in the desert,
say a quarter mile away,
when they all turned on their suits,
the force fields from around those suits
merged into one.
And I speak from direct experience.
You would swear there was a giant white floating horse
coming at you from out in the desert.
Now, that horse could, when they were in that formation,
the reason I call it the high-speed horse formation
is because when they, I personally watched them,
when they wanted to go somewhere without,
when they were out hiking, say like,
and they wanted to go somewhere fast,
they could form up into that formation
and they could reach speeds of 100 miles an hour
over the desert by floating up above the ground
and just going zoom.
I remember,
I used to watch them play at the runways
at Indian Springs Air Base on summer nights
as the way tobogganists did,
where they would pretend they were airplanes taking off
and then when they got to the end,
they would lift up and go over the fence around the runway
and go out in the desert and turn around
and pretend they were airplanes doing touch and goes.
Why do you think they were allowed to operate independently
on kind of American military grounds?
So the superior...
The base for them was like a foreign embassy.
And they've been here since the Ice Age.
Do you think it was the nuclear testing
that created some sort of Wheeler Tunnel or something
that they traveled through?
Or like, why there?
Why do you think they set up shop there?
Consider, I'm certain that the Greys got here first
and they were here before the last Ice Age.
And that the Tall Whites,
they got here second
and they were here by at least the middle of the last Ice Age.
And the Norwegians with 24 teeth
got here towards the end of the last Ice Age.
The Tall Whites have the best technology.
The Greys have really good technology.
The Norwegians are just barely able to travel in space
and make it here.
When you look at the bases
and where the Tall Whites and the Greys are,
you have to look at the way they were in the Ice Age.
There's a place out in the deserts that I was in.
It's out in one of the most desolate sections
of the Western deserts that you can imagine.
There's an L-shaped valley
with desert mountains on both sides.
And then there's a valley on the northern side.
But in the southern side,
the valley is an L-shaped valley
and there's a dry lake bed,
a small,
dry lake bed on the southern side
and a huge amphitheater-type set of ground
that the Greys farmed during the Ice Age.
And in the mountain on the west,
they'd cut 13 tunnels in the mountain on the west
and they used them as a granary.
And the first one on the north
was larger than the others,
and it was large enough for their deep spacecraft
to come in and pick up grain.
And the 13th one overlooked the fields.
And at the top of the L-shaped valley
and at the bottom of the L-shaped valley,
the mountains form a constriction.
So if you were a gray teenager with a appropriate weapon
and you were sitting there,
you could monitor both entrances.
And so if any Ice Age animals came in to eat the grain,
because they're plant eaters,
the tall whites and the greys do not eat meat,
they're only plant eaters,
you could keep them out and protect,
keep them from eating your food.
And when you asked,
and when you looked at the valley on the west,
you could see the ancient,
you could see the ancient water lines
from how high the lake had been
during different stages of the Ice Age.
Now, central Nevada was never glaciated.
It was only,
it was just that in the Ice Age,
because the weather was different,
it rained lots and lots,
like it does in Kentucky.
And so those dry,
those lake beds were not glacial lakes.
They weren't glacial carved.
They were poluvial lakes,
the Latin word for rain.
And therefore the bottom,
those lake beds were flat
and the land leading into them
were perfect places to farm.
And what you were looking at was a granary,
a farm that the greys used during the Ice Age.
So it sounds like there are all these unique reasons
as to why as an extraterrestrial presence,
you'd set up shop in that area.
This is a really interesting question.
It's a really interesting point.
Something I kept coming back to
while preparing for this conversation
was this strange possibility of
what if Area 51's weirdness didn't start
because it's a military base?
What if the base was put there
because of a pre-existing weirdness in the region?
As Charles points out,
the broader pattern is hard to ignore.
Many of the most restricted military ranges
and test sites sit in the same kind of landscapes,
remote deserts,
mountain valleys,
and high plains,
and sometimes,
Native American burial grounds.
Sure, there are practical reasons for this
when it comes to testing weapons and spy planes,
but often these places were tied up in UFO sightings,
cryptic creatures,
electromagnetic anomalies,
before military bases were even placed on them.
Many were even seen to be portals to other dimensions.
Maybe it isn't just a coincidence.
Maybe the military wasn't just picking up empty land,
but claiming ground
that was very unusual.
To put it bluntly,
maybe military bases often like to co-locate themselves
with very strange paranormal areas.
Skinwalker Ranch in northeastern Utah
is perhaps the most public example.
I've been there myself,
and you've no doubt heard the stories.
It's probably the most scientifically studied
paranormal hotspot in the world,
at least on the civil side.
Multiple UFO sightings,
glowing orbs,
cattle mutilations,
and even reports of orange portals,
opening up in the air.
But it also has its former military connections.
There was a U.S. Army outpost in the region
in the 19th century,
and today it sits not far from Dugway Proving Grounds.
In the 2000s,
billionaire and government contractor Robert Bigelow
received Pentagon funding through the OSAP program
to research the ranch.
Why, you might ask?
Well, folklore from the Utah tribe
had already marked the land as cursed,
prowled by shapeshifters.
That was long before the Pentagon
made it a research site.
And if you zoom out,
the geography is interesting too.
You can draw a rough triangle
between Area 51,
Skinwalker Ranch,
and Roswell.
Other paranormal hotspots
with co-located military activity
exist all over the United States.
For example,
Sedona, Arizona.
Local legends speak of tunnels
and gateways hidden in the cliffs,
where star people pass through
shimmering portals.
The Bradshaw Ranch there
became famous for UFO sightings
investigated not long ago
by Ross Coulthard.
Eventually, the site was taken over
by the U.S. government,
a move that raised some eyebrows.
Why seize a random rural property
in Arizona
unless there was something
they felt needed securing?
To this day,
locals still report
black helicopters circling overhead
and interference with drones near the area.
It fits the pattern.
Land fenced off
not just for practical reasons,
but because of whatever it is said
to be in the land itself.
Land that seems full
of electromagnetic anomalies,
and perhaps the same tunnels
in land that are occupied
by the tall whites.
And that brings us back to Nevada.
It's easy to forget
that Area 51 isn't just one base.
It's part of a vast test range
anchored by Nellis,
swallowing up thousands
of square miles of desert.
Charles gets into this
in just a moment,
but the history of how
this whole area
ended up getting claimed
by the government
doesn't quite add up.
Especially when it became
a herd of desert sheep,
suddenly becoming an issue
of national security.
And it begs the very important question,
how much of this pattern
extends overseas?
Look at where the United States
has planted some of its overseas bases.
Diego Garcia in the Indian Ocean,
Pine Gap in outback Australia,
sprawling compounds
in Iraq and Afghanistan.
Some of these sites
already had their own unusual reputations
amongst locals.
Or maybe some other uses
to our alien visitors
from out of town.
Do you think it's a coincidence then
that you get Area 51
and some of the most top secret
advanced R&D
when it comes to the American military
co-located on that area?
I subscribe to the Marine Corps theory.
If it happened once,
it would be a coincidence.
If it happened twice,
I'm sorry,
if it was happened once,
it would be random.
If it happened twice,
it would be a coincidence.
But the third time you see it's there,
somebody planned it.
Okay?
Yeah.
Now, remember,
what else is out there?
The Desert Game Range National Park.
Okay?
Now, the Desert Game Range
was set up
in the time of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
Okay?
It was, what,
I talk about it a lot,
I talk about it in my book,
and it was like 1935 or 1937.
For some reason,
FDR just got up all by himself
and after talking with a single Army colonel,
Army Air Force colonel,
decided that the desert bighorn sheep
who live in the mountains like Sheep Peak,
for which it's named,
and the mountains to the east
must be
an endangered species.
You say, wait a moment,
this is 1937.
I didn't realize we had endangered species
till 1970 or something.
This was 1937.
And by executive order said,
we got to make that a protected area
to protect the desert bighorn sheep.
They're white.
And if you're out there hiking
and you see something,
in the words of the park rangers,
that looks like a human
looking at you from over the sagebrush,
which may be as tall as six feet,
don't look back,
especially if it looks like a woman with children,
because the bighorn sheep don't like that.
They'll attack you.
Just look away and walk away.
And in 1937,
in order to protect the sheep,
and that,
we're talking before World War II,
Franklin Roosevelt
and the Army Air Force decided
that they would station
a battalion of anti-aircraft guns
with live ammo
to protect it.
Okay?
So in case it,
so it wouldn't be subject
to Japanese air attack.
And it was all that specific area.
And that specific area.
Right.
And that was the desert bighorn,
before there was an Area 51,
before there was a Nellis Gunnery Range,
before there were,
was it Camp Mercury or anything,
there was the Desert Southwest Game Range.
So that's the first time there.
And you say that,
so the sheep are being protected
by an anti-aircraft cruise
that have live ammo
and they're open to fire
at any airplane that goes across there in 1937.
And FDR just said,
well, I want the sheep to be safe.
And that's why it's called Sheep Peak.
And you say,
when you look at it,
Sheep Peak seems like a pretty easy place to climb.
Why is it that the first time,
it is a matter of record,
that it was climbed,
that anyone climbed it,
was 1970?
Okay.
You say,
well,
remember we did,
we did Mount Everest before that,
right?
Well, it sounds like,
you know,
protecting sheep with,
anti-aircraft technology,
the most advanced at the time.
Yeah.
It seems like if you'd fire a few,
if you'd fire a few live rounds,
wouldn't you kind of scare them a little bit,
right?
Yeah.
So based on your rule,
if it's like,
you know,
fool me once,
okay,
fool me twice,
fine.
Fool me three times,
you know,
it's a,
that's sort of a,
you know,
that's not a coincidence anymore.
What's the second time?
Is there a second time
before Area 51,
which gets set up in the 50s,
that suspicious military
or covert activity
occurs in the region
that might have to do
with the ET presence?
Well,
remember how good
their technology is,
the technology of the whites
and the technology of the grays.
And I do not exaggerate.
I speak from direct experience.
When you say,
if they came here
in the Ice Age,
and in order to,
and they're plant eaters,
and in order for,
to get a little help
with harvesting grain
and doing manual labor
and things like that,
there's nobody out in Nevada,
where would they get that from?
Remember how good
their technology is.
And I speak from direct experience.
If they wanted to use
the scout craft,
which is,
oh,
the tall white scout craft
or the gray scout craft,
which I,
both of which
I've personally seen.
And in the time
I've been talking,
if they wanted to say,
lift off from the backyard
and go to the moon
and circumnavigate the moon
to check up on what's going on
in the far side of the moon
and return and land
in the backyard right here,
they would have already done so.
That's how good
their technology is.
One of the things
I personally watched them do
from a distance,
because if you get too close
the fields will burn you
like a microwave,
but like from a distance
of say like two and a half,
three miles,
was to lift,
was to go onto the scout craft
and sit down in the seats,
no seat belts or anything,
just chairs like this
and lift power up
and power up the,
not the outer coils,
but just the bottom
and control coils
and lift off until
they were floating
perhaps as far off the desert
or above the sagebrush
as the height the camera is.
And then take a few seconds,
like 30 seconds,
to power up completely
the outer coils.
It takes a few seconds to do so.
When they do so,
before they do so,
the craft looks
the way you're expecting.
If you saw a helicopter out there,
you'd see the actual metal
of the helicopter.
But after they're powered up,
they just look real fuzzy white
like a Tic Tac
because they're surrounded
with force fields.
You no longer see
the actual metal,
you just see the force field
and the way it's fuzzing over light
and interacting with it.
Once they're powered up,
they're ready for
high speed maneuvers.
Let's get into it.
If they choose to go
straight down the line of sight,
they can go seven miles
at an average speed
of 8,000 to 12,000 miles an hour,
stop, power down, and set down.
And in the process,
they would have taken
more than 15,000 Gs starting
and 15,000 Gs stopping,
just sitting there
in the room like this.
And in case you're wondering
how much that is,
10,000 Gs will liquefy,
that's steel.
What's the,
is the speed of light
is like 86,000 miles per hour?
186,000.
186,000, okay.
Miles per second.
And they can do.
So if they're going
eight to 10,000 miles per hour,
there's still massive difference
between that and speed of light.
They're not even in low gear.
Yeah, not even in low gear, wow.
If they go,
if they do that
and they choose to go sideways,
they'll go side,
they'll just seem to blink out.
You'll be looking there
and they'll just seem
to disappear before your eyes
because they will have accelerated
and moved to the side
so fast your eyes can't follow.
I speak from direct experience.
And if you're looking up
and straight up Indian Springs Valley
and they choose to pop over
to Dogbone Valley
and come down
and then come in one
of the northern passes
to see what you're doing,
it'll look like they just blinked out there
and magically reappeared over there
less than a second or two later.
They're in the hands of a skilled pilot.
A lot of people
who still believe in Einstein
will mistakenly say
they went to another dimension.
Really, they haven't.
They've done it,
if you were in the way,
the craft would run into you.
There is no such thing
as wormholes
or warping space and time.
What you're warping
isn't space and time.
You're interacting
with other force fields
or all matter has.
And, you know,
the same way that you might have
an electric field of different shapes
or a magnetic field of different shapes.
But time never slows down.
Time never runs in reverse.
Time is just time.
It always goes forward.
Have you ever flown in a craft?
Yes, yeah.
A couple of times I did.
What was that like?
Well, I was in the cargo hold at the time
because there was,
as I describe in my books,
the day after I thought
I had broken my kneecap
and then it healed up,
there was the next morning
when they came down to get me
and take me up to their base
up at area 53
to see if I needed a surgery on my knee.
And was it the Tall Whites?
Yeah, only,
and when I got up there,
the American generals were there
and medical people were up there too.
And I didn't.
I just bruised it.
But the Tall Whites
had to prove to the Americans
that they were telling them
to correct or wanted to prove that.
And so they came down and grabbed me
and put me in the hold of the cargo shop.
And I still remember the trip up there
and the trip back.
Where did they go?
Did you leave?
No, they just lifted off
and we just went gently up the valley,
perhaps 100 feet off the ground.
And I remember flying around range fours
and made the turn around range four
and then going up the valley to the,
they were going to the scout craft,
the back entrance to their scout craft hangar.
And the door was open and we went in there
and then there was a whole bunch of men there,
but there were also an American general
and some American medical people
and the six sergeants,
chief master sergeants
that were the human guards
for the human generals
and the teacher in range four Harry.
And it was just like sitting here in a chair,
only in the cargo hold.
And they didn't do it as,
they didn't totally power up
because they didn't have to.
And it was like sitting here in the chair
and having the whole room just be lifted up
and taken and come back.
And it was remarkably unremarkable.
The important part was
that they thought they had electronically hypnotized me,
but their equipment doesn't work
if you're sick
or if you're angry
or if you're really tired.
And since I was,
even though my knee was not broken,
I was still experiencing some pain.
You know, it was still tender.
It meant that the way my thoughts,
the blood flow in the brain was,
was somewhat different
than the way it would normally be.
And so therefore,
when you use the electronic hypnotism on me,
that would normally have worked
when I was,
when I was ordinary,
or if I was healthy and well rested,
it didn't quite do the job.
It's almost like anesthesia that doesn't work
during surgery or something.
Yeah.
So speaking of...
So I got to remember it.
Yeah.
Range four hearing knew that was the case,
but that was all he could do, yeah.
Why do you think they chose you for all of this?
Why do you think you were sort of picked
to be endowed with this knowledge?
One time I asked a different person
who was one of the top,
identified himself as one of the top three psychiatrists
at the CIA.
One of the time I asked him why they chose me.
Okay.
Because I said I thought there were lots of men
that were better at going out in the desert
and surviving and doing,
fixing trucks and so on than myself.
A lot of weather observers with more experience
and so on than me.
And he told me the following.
He said that,
and he had like nine PhDs hanging on the wall
for different facets of psychiatry.
And he was a very nice guy.
He was surprisingly young, like in his thirties.
He said that when he studied psychiatry,
he was told that there was 105 different
psychological defenses that humans might use.
The most famous is whistling in the dark.
Okay.
He said that
most humans only use one or two at the most.
That one of the projects that he and the others usually did
was trying to train colonels and generals
on how to have more psychological defenses.
They were hoping to get generals to use three,
or they always want them to use three.
They were hoping they could get them to use four or five.
This is of the 105.
And he said that he had told his,
the other guys that were with him,
psychiatrists that some of the,
there were a couple of,
there were some generals he was trying to train.
He thought he was going to get them to learn seven,
and he couldn't.
They were going to hang in there at three.
He said that the first time he met me,
he was shocked because in the first 15 minutes,
he saw me use the first 70 out of the 105.
And he was a certain I could use the other hundred,
the other, the remainder of the 105.
And you can see it in my books.
He said the 41 men that went out before me,
who all came back compromised and some of them burned,
he said the problem they had,
in his opinion,
was that they recognized what they were up against,
or something of what they were up against,
before they understood how they were going to,
had decided how they were going to react.
Okay.
And he said that in,
and therefore what happened was in just the first encounter,
their psychological defenses got destroyed.
And he said that the reason they sent me,
he said,
if there ever was a person to send,
it would be you.
He said it's because they'll never lay a glove on you.
They'll never,
that,
you know,
that no matter what happens,
you have a defense for it.
Okay.
And they had evaluated that prior to sending you out.
Yeah.
To commune with the Ethiopians.
They'll let,
they have a,
you know,
and you can see it in there in my,
there was a time when I thought that the extraterrestrials,
the extraterrestrial lady I was looking at,
that I was hallucinating.
And I was kind of surprised because I was kind of thinking that if I was going to hallucinate,
I was alone out in the desert,
I was young and single,
that if I was going to hallucinate,
that it would be more like a Las Vegas show girl.
And she wasn't,
you know,
and I thought,
my God,
how sick am I?
I'm not even,
you know,
see,
and she was laughing.
She,
cause she could tell that I was thinking because of her electronic equipment,
you see.
See,
and there was a time when I was,
there was a time when I thought that it,
that I must be short on vitamins when they would come into my barracks at Indian Springs.
And I would get up and I would see the children playing.
And I thought,
golly,
I knew I should have drank more milk.
It's for supper.
I must be short on vitamins and milk.
And so I would take more vitamins and they would still keep coming.
There was a time.
You're also debriefing with generals who are admitting that this is a phenomenon.
That they're aware of,
and that they're kind of working alongside these ETs.
Is that right?
No,
I'm never debriefed.
You're never debriefed.
I'm never briefed.
I'm never debriefed.
But you're,
aren't you talking to the generals about?
Not only,
that's not an accident.
My orders are,
I can never be briefed.
I can never be debriefed.
And the reason is very simple.
Uh-huh.
Because the tall whites,
like the teacher,
can tell what a person is thinking,
even if they're not talking.
So,
you know,
it's,
well,
if you're debriefed,
and they're very touchy about their children,
if a briefing person were to say,
what kind of mother is the teacher?
You know,
how does she treat her little girl?
I mean,
she was lost in the sagebrush,
and you,
you saved her life.
How did they let that happen?
See,
then they wouldn't have to ask me to tell them about it.
they could tell it by just reading my line,
my thoughts.
The next day,
the next thing they would demand,
is that somebody,
like that officer,
be delivered to them out in the desert,
and he wouldn't live another moment.
Okay?
Yeah.
And she,
I wouldn't have to say anything,
or do anything,
or say,
oh,
because she could just tell,
yeah,
I read Charlie,
and I see that happened.
See?
So,
when I say that no one could ever ask me questions,
I could never be debriefed,
nothing I would do would ever be classified.
Like,
no one could,
I mean,
they couldn't even,
they couldn't even inspect me.
If they wanted to talk to me,
they physically had to come out to the parking lot of the chow hall at Indian Springs between noon and 1230,
and I would meet them there if I felt like meeting them,
or if I didn't,
then they would just,
and before they went out,
they would have to check in with the base commander at Nellis,
and when they came back,
they had to go directly from checking on base to the base commander,
and say,
yeah,
I looked healthy,
and I could,
and they couldn't come out and inspect my barracks or see anything.
Have you,
you mentioned the CIA psychiatrist who said that you had all these psychological defenses.
Mm-hmm.
And that sort of allowed you to enter into relations with the ETs.
It allowed me.
And come back intact.
No,
it allowed me to protect my thoughts,
the person I am,
before admitting to myself,
they are real,
and I know what I'm gonna do.
Have you ever heard the name Kit Green?
Is that familiar to you at all?
Mm-hmm.
It doesn't ring a bell,
but I probably heard him.
But see,
like,
see,
the first thing I agreed,
the first agreement I made with him was,
after realizing they were real,
that I asked him that whenever they came around me,
that they talk between themselves,
if they were talking between themselves,
or with me in a way that I could hear,
to speak English,
because it frightened me,
if they were talking between themselves,
and it sometimes sounded like horse winnings,
or bird calls.
And they agreed.
And then the second one was,
that if I saw them out in the desert,
like if I came over a rise,
and there was one sitting on a rock,
I understood that it was easy for me to sneak up on him,
behind him,
and surprise him,
because I didn't want to do that.
I would just stop where I was,
and stand where I was,
and sing a song,
and let them know I was there.
And then if they wanted to come closer,
I would just stand there,
and they could walk up towards me,
and stop whenever they wanted to.
I wouldn't pursue,
I wouldn't close the gap.
And if they got too close to me,
so that it,
I started feeling intimidated.
I would start backing away,
and they would stop.
And then when we had decided how far apart
we were going to be physically,
then we could communicate.
Your wife, Marie-Therese,
mentioned that you actually were sent out initially.
Initially I was supposed to go out from,
after doing my basic training at Lackland.
Then I was put in P.A.T. stands,
P.A.T. standing.
You know, that was airmen,
airmen waiting for security clearance.
Okay?
And those airmen that were going to get a security clearance
and be sent to San Angeles, Texas
for Security School 101,
were supposed to wait there for like three weeks or so.
Okay?
Now, the security clearance you're waiting for
is whatever the government decides to give you,
but it's supposed to be the top secret clearance.
Okay?
Now, the security training,
the people who are sent to San Angeles, Texas,
are waiting to get their orders to San Angeles, Texas.
However, in my case,
they've issued two sets of orders,
the real ones to San Angeles, Texas,
and the cover orders
to the weather training school
at Schooner Air Force Base, Illinois.
The idea is that the captain
who is in charge of those guys,
who has a safe for classified material that's locked,
this is 1965, times have all changed since then,
he's the one that will give out my orders.
The day sergeant can give out all the rest of the orders.
Okay?
Yeah.
Because the day sergeant,
because my clearance is going to be a higher clearance than theirs.
Well, the Friday that they came in,
the captain is off playing golf.
Now, as a military officer,
he's supposed to be on duty.
He's off playing golf and left the sergeant in command.
The sergeant does not have the clearance
to know about my orders.
So when the clearance comes,
the orders come in for everybody else,
and we were all in the same class together at boot camp,
I think a mistake has been made.
Okay?
They get their orders.
I go in with them.
There's no orders.
I say, well,
because my cover orders are in a different location than their orders,
but they're not locked up.
See?
They're just in the temporary outbox.
Well, I asked the sergeant.
I got no orders.
Aren't I going to weather school too?
So the sergeant goes and gets those orders and says,
oh, yeah, here's your orders,
and hands them to me to go to weather training school.
So I go out and I get on the bus.
You know, I got my stuff packed.
Now, my drill sergeant had made a very special point.
He said, any time you do anything in the military,
keep two copies of your orders because you can't trust your officers.
Right?
Genius, right?
I keep two copies, right?
Okay?
So I get on the bus.
I'm not on the travel mass, but I got orders.
So what?
So they throw me on the airplane,
and they send me to shoot at Air Force Base, Illinois.
If you can't shoot them,
that place, okay?
Well, I'm in the base,
and everybody else is getting beat up.
And I'm getting paid,
and I'm at weather school,
and I'm the best student in the class.
And after like six weeks,
I still haven't been paid.
And so I go and I ask the command,
my immediate commander,
can I go see?
I'm not getting paid.
He sends me over to the base payroll offices,
and they look at their records,
and they're panicky.
You're on this base,
and they send me back to weather school.
I go back to weather school,
and two MP air policemen and a dog come in
and grab me
and march me over to the base commander's office.
I'm a little terrified.
And the base commander says,
Airman Hall,
if you have a copy of your orders showing you
that you're supposed to be on this base,
then you're going to be a happy man,
and whoever gave you the orders
is not going to be very happy.
But if you don't have a copy of the orders,
the man who gave them to you
is going to be a happy man,
and you're not going to be a soldier.
You're not going to be a very happy soldier
because the generals tell me
you're too valuable a man
to be wasted at this school.
I had two copies in my wallet.
I said, thank you, Sergeant,
Master Sergeant Peoples.
I graced his hand.
I said, you need another one?
I can copy this, right?
I was a happy man.
They said, well,
we'll decide what to do, right?
So they'd been looking for me
at San Angeles, Texas,
for six weeks.
The FBI had been looking for me
at my house in London.
Nobody had found me.
I go back,
and the sergeant comes out and says,
you're going to Nellis, okay?
Wow.
Yeah.
They gave me the usual wish list.
When you finish weather school,
name three places you'd like to go.
I said Germany, England,
and March Air Force Base, Los Angeles.
And they said, no, you're going to Nellis.
How soon after?
How soon after you're stationed at Nellis
do you encounter this abandoned weather station
and meet your first tall white?
Well, the first time
that I heard tell of the tall whites
at Nellis
was at my very first duty session
with another airman,
which I describe in my book.
He was the airman that had been on leave
for several weeks
because he claimed that
the Nellis weather station was haunted.
And it's not the one you see there today.
It was the old one that was the northeast end
of the base operations building.
The base operations building
was a very nice building for its day,
as was the weather station.
I describe it in my book.
And it had something very important.
It was the military version
of an airport terminal.
And it had something very important.
It had clean restrooms.
The next clean restroom
was a mile away
in a group of barracks
they were still building.
To get to another clean restroom,
you had to go a mile and a half away.
Okay?
He claimed that
when he was working
night graveyard,
and he was in his,
he had been in its military,
he was on his fourth year,
that he,
the previous winter that
he thought ghosts,
you and I would say,
a group of five tall white aliens,
had come in off the runway,
off the tarmac,
unlocking the pad of the glass doors
between the base operations,
the interior of the base operations building
and the tarmac,
because one of the force fields
will make every piece of material
repel every other piece of material
and just pop every lock open.
And that,
when he came in,
there was one waiting outside,
standing guard,
one holding the door open,
or,
and one,
and then,
that's two men,
and then three women,
one holding open the door
to the bath,
or,
to the bathroom,
another one inside,
holding,
helping them hold open the door
to the bathroom,
while the third one
was using the ladies' restroom
and that they were rotating
so that they'd come in
to use the restroom.
He didn't,
he,
although he described them doing that,
he didn't appreciate
what he was describing.
He thought they were ghosts.
He panicked immediately
and started screaming,
locked himself in the doorway
and called the base air police,
only to discover that
the Nellis Base commander said,
no,
the air police cannot come beyond
the road junction a mile away.
He's on his own.
Okay?
Now, I know from firsthand experience
that he was telling the truth,
because there came a day
when I was working graveyard,
actually a whole bunch of days,
on Sunday night
when everything was empty,
when that would happen.
And the reason that they came
was because they're just like us.
The bathroom that was a mile down,
which the mechanics down in that hangar,
airport hangar,
thought was haunted,
was occasionally visited
by tall white men
who had to go to the bathroom.
And it was a mess,
never cleaned.
Okay?
And if you're out with two men
and three women
who wanted a clean bathroom,
and the one a mile and a half down
was too far
and wasn't suitable,
and you said,
where do we want to go to the bathroom?
You'd say, I know just the place.
It's the one in the base ops.
And on Sunday night,
there's nobody around.
There's the weather observer,
and he's usually sleeping at night,
like he should.
Okay?
He's not supposed to,
but usually they did.
Actually, that was a great place to sleep.
I myself didn't,
but I had too much fun reading books and stuff.
And so,
and the guy that I was,
he was my OJT instructor,
he also claimed that on a different night
when he was in there,
that one of them came
and peeked at him around the corner
and said, don't worry,
the women just want to use the restroom.
He screamed and called the police again,
and they wouldn't come.
And he had an idea.
He was a nervous breakdown.
So, you know,
and that happened to me.
I said, yeah,
don't forget the candy bar machine.
You know,
you guys may be hungry.
Right?
And that's what psychological defenses do for you.
You see,
that's a difference.
And,
but that's the first one.
He told me the story,
but I didn't actually see the tall whites on that night.
Then a few nights later,
when he had been given an honorable discharge,
because the Pentagon insisted
that he and I alone in the warehouse on Sunday night,
alone in the weather station together,
work at least one duty shift.
And then he would be given an honorable discharge
of section eight,
which he was.
Then when I was with my next duty shift,
my next OJT instructor,
and he was working a double shift,
I was working swing shift.
When I,
came left at midnight,
and I was trying to hurry to get to the base up,
to the base chow hall.
As I was walking back the mile or so to my barracks,
one of the new ones being built,
I would end up,
I,
when I turned around,
following me was the tall white girl that,
the 12 year old.
And I was about a quarter mile down from the base up,
from the weather station and back by the white elephant.
Was the teacher and two bridge for Harry
and another tall white guard happily watching me
from a distance.
And all she was doing was just following me,
intentionally showing herself.
At the time,
I,
when you talk about what good are such psychological defenses
at the time,
I couldn't believe my eyes,
even though they matched what the guy had told me
just a few days ago.
And I,
I,
And,
and,
I,
and.
And so she was actually,
after going a few steps, and there she was. She still followed me. And I had been reading a book
on the Titanic, which I can talk about later. And in the Titanic, it described a group of angels
who came in a craft, one of the lifeboats, and landed on the ledge of one of the icebergs and
dropped wreaths for people in the water to use as life preservers, which didn't work.
And how one of the angels was good at floating out over the water and dropping her hand.
And when I turned around and I was just watching her, she smiled. That girl, she lifted up,
turned up the power on her suit, lifted up a little bit further to the top of her feet,
were about as far off the ground as the top, not as top, almost the top of that chair,
chair, flew off.
Over beside the sidewalk, which was over the grass, and saw, and went over the grass a little
bit, and saw on the grass something that, a piece of wrapper or perhaps a quarter or something that
interested her. And with her feet still in the air, bent, lowered her shoulders, reached down
on the grass and picked it up, assuming the very same.
The same position that was described in the book on the Titanic that I had previously read,
like that night or two nights before, described by the lady in the Survivor of the Lifeboat
that was picked up by the Carpathia as described in the book that I was reading.
And like she was the very same girl, and considering that the 12 whites live 600,
800 years, 10 times longer than we do, she could have been.
And when I looked at it, I was stunned. And I still didn't make the association
between those people and extraterrestrials. That's what psychological defenses do for you.
And I decided that I must just be sleepwalking, or there must be something with me mentally.
And I went home, and I went back to my barracks, and life continued.
Steve McLaughlin , Let's get into the Hall photon theory because,
and just to set this up for the audience, also in the 30s in 1935,
Einstein said, Rosen and Padol стать, come up with their sort of spooky action
at a distance, entanglement, and it's known as Einstein's dilemma because Einstein
had always kind of almost put a governor on reality. The speed limit of reality is the
speed of light. And yet, with photons observably you see this sort of entanglement effect where
optical properties, various optical properties, seem to mirror one another at vast distances
just instantaneously. And so how is the Hall photon theory an update on that? And how does
that unlock faster-than-light travel in the form of a spacecraft? Well, to begin with, I'd like to
thank you for this nice interview. And if I don't fit in having us on your podcast, I'd like to
congratulate you on just out-thinking Einstein, okay? When you say, what's it feel like to be
smarter than Albert Einstein? I say, well, I know a guy. It's not just me, because what you say is
correct. And the easiest way to see it is starting with the way Einstein did with the
Michelson-Morley experiment of 1897, okay? Which was a failure. In 1897, everyone thought that a
photon of light
had only two force fields, an electric field and a magnetic field, that oscillated together, okay?
And then they did the Michelson-Morley experiment, and then they wanted to interpret it
as though it were a experiment that you would do with little boats crossing a river and going up
and down in the river, when they didn't know anything about the... They thought they knew
everything about the... They thought they knew everything about the... They thought they knew
everything there was to know about the photon, that there was only two force fields, so they
could pretend that they knew everything about how a photon looks like a little boat going across
a river, okay? When the experiment failed, then nobody wanted to say there has to be more structure
to the photon than what we know about. Nobody wanted to do that, okay? James Clerk Maxwell had
done his equations, and they didn't want to say,
there's more force fields that Maxwell's equations don't include, but should, okay? And they oscillate
too. They wanted to say, we know everything there is to know about the photon. And then they wanted
to say, and we know everything about the river and the banks and stuff and the little boats that
cross it. So now they had reasoned themselves into a corner, so why did the experiment fail?
And they monkeyed around like that until Einstein, and they finally asked Einstein...
But I think...
Think of it as a failure to detect the ether, the Michelson-Morley experiments. Is that right,
to think a medium through which photons would be carried?
That would make sense, yeah, that there was no ether, but then that left the question,
so why isn't there at least some change? Why did the experiment totally fail, okay? Along the way,
they ignored things about the experiment. The first one is that if you do the experiment with one photon at
a time in the interferometer, you get the same results. And that means that the photon has to
be split in two for that to work. Today, we call that photon entanglement. But back then, they said,
well, I don't know, spooky at a distance, right? And then if you do it with photons of just red
light, then you get the same results, but the...
bright bands of light are still red light. And so, therefore, the explanation that the photons
would constructively interfere and destructively interfere can't be correct, because if they
constructively interfered, they would have to change color. Blue photons have twice the energy
of red photons, so that would mean you would be sending in blue light,
or sending in red light, and looking at interference patterns of red light. But that's
not the case. All that's happening in the interferometer is that the photons are being
steered into bands of red photons. That needs another force field to do the steering.
So what is, if you have, in traditional electromagnetism, classical electrodynamics,
you have an electric field, a magnetic field,
and a wave, and they're all sort of running perpendicular to one another, what other
field types do you think exist in the whole photon theory?
A whole bunch, okay? Like what?
Okay. And remember, the force fields can be different force strengths. The electric force,
magnetic force field, is considered pound for pound to be like, what, a trillion times,
might not have that number right, 100 million times more powerful pound for pound than the
force of gravity. Yeah, it's 10 to the 40th.
But because the force of gravity is weaker pound for pound than the electromagnetic field,
the force of gravity can move further than light, okay? So the force of gravity from our galaxy can
affect the nearby galaxy, the Andromeda galaxy, at 2.7 million light years, whereas the force of
electricity from our galaxy can move further than light. So the force of gravity from our galaxy can
not, right? But Einstein wanted to ruin that analogy by saying, to protect his own reputation,
I guess, I have no idea why, trying to say that nothing could travel faster than light,
not even gravity. But obviously, if gravity can travel further than light, it must be traveling
faster than light. If you look at the symmetry of the Andromeda galaxy, and you say, well,
it's, what, 10,000, 100,000 light years, 200,000 light years across, and that means that,
and it's so well organized, gravity must be traveling trillions of times faster than light.
Otherwise, if the stars were trying to do that, and gravity was only traveling at the speed of
light, they'd all bump into each other. Why do you, so is gravity in your model,
also orders of magnitude weaker than electromagnetism? Because if it's traveling
that far and having an effect, a pulling effect between mass bodies?
If it's weaker, then it could go further. And see, in the photon...
How does that hold? If it's weaker, it goes further?
Because it's like a milk truck delivering milk, right? If it's going to go down a street and hit
every house, then it's going to stop and interact along the way, or at least stand ready to.
But if it's going to just do one house here and a house 10 miles down, the guy can go into high gear.
But I would think of, like, attenuation as being, you know, like a way of being,
you know, a certain amount of strength, and then it attenuates.
The only way a force field can attenuate is, say, like, I'll say, like, gravity,
mm-hmm, is for there to be an interaction cross-section
put up by a...
another piece of matter, or energy, somewhere down the road, and then when it's traveling,
it's not trying to interact with the electric field. It's trying to interact with another
gravity field, and those are attractive interactions. And if it casts...
And because it doesn't have to, there is no interaction cross-section between...
gravity and, say, an electric field it would be traveling through,
then it could travel much, much faster, much, much further.
That's what the neutrino is. Mm-hmm.
The neutrino, we're told, can travel through...
If everything between the center of the Sun and here were solid gravity,
the neutrino could travel through it all and not interact with anything.
Yep.
So therefore, a neutrino can travel many, many times faster than light.
Okay. However, you say...
well what about the neutrinos that say are measured at the CERN reactor? Well if they're
going to interact using electricity and magnetism and they have to slow to that speed the electricity
and magnetism to perform the interaction because time doesn't change. Time is always flying at the
same rate. They're all in the same time frame. Do you think we have neutrino detectors?
That's why neutrinos are so hard to detect. Yeah but there are rumors that we have
neutrino detectors like at the south pole and you know. The whole photon theory says that within
that light is a bundle of force fields and there have to there have so there have to be a whole
bunch of force fields in the photon okay and you must have to have variations of photons that have
different colors.
Collections of those different force fields because you have photons and neutrinos which
you see which are very similar and those photons that means that even though photons
that we're used to are limited by the speed of light because it because the electric field and
the magnetic field have interaction cross sections that go that you know the permit permittivity of
free space and so on right okay that it has to touch base it has to vibrate all those piano
wires if you will when you if you have those other force fields be weak force fields like
the neutrino is surrounded by weak interaction force fields they don't got to vibrate the
electromagnetic wires you see they only got to vibrate their own wires they may not have to do it
if you say well what are the permittivity of free space for those other force fields
they're much less than the ones for electricity and magnetism therefore when you say let me compute
the speed of light for those force fields as i do in beyond relativity you come up with a speed a
trillion times faster.
Charles using the whole photon theory how would you build the ufo and how would you basically propel your
yourself faster than light?
well i'll give you some general principles okay based on what i personally saw
in the deserts the first thing is the ufo must be a smooth ellipsoid like a new uh like like an egg
or a tic tac because the first the first principle of designing the different force fields and so on
is there cannot be any turbulence what about a saucer does that rule that out it depends on how
the edges of the saucer are it can't and it can't have anything concave an example of something
concave is if like on the camera you have the lens and it's shaped nice and then around it is a ring
that sticks out
and in between where the lens meets the ring this concave if that were the shape
of a of a spacecraft that you were trying to use to propel yourself through space
you would be strictly limited to less than about 80 percent the speed of light.
Because the force fields in that region would obey einstein's theory of relativity because because in
the additionally- problème Jerry neutron not safety in the space he would follow the Einstein's
theory of relativity because this is aывer , this is an unit of relativity and we are used to we would get
that incredible amount of 1944 degrees Celsius and that the force field is almost too much right in our
body or just the way that you look at it 20% ofopheles here as oppose dealt with this.
On the other hand shunderson knows had a very complex field of relativity that's that was interested in
galaxy poppedering or varsity ... it was definitely the only one student that i saw in our
because they're not streamlined in that area,
they would go turbulent.
And once they go turbulent,
the force fields will bump into each other.
The heating can go to infinity.
The amount of energy that's lost in that little zone
could go to infinity.
But convex is fine?
Sorry?
Convex is fine.
Concave creates this turbulent kind of...
Yeah, but if you took that lens
and made it a complete ellipsoidal sphere of glass
and you use that shape where there's no sharp edges,
there's no concave edges,
where there's just always egg-shaped,
then when you surround it with a bubble of force fields,
they won't go turbulent
because they're streamlined for high-speed travel.
When you do that,
and you start accelerating towards the speed of light,
it'll just continue accelerating
as though the speed of light weren't there.
It'll just go right on through.
When you hear stories like Ryan Graves, Navy pilot,
talk about a sphere inside a cube
or other kind of exotic-looking objects
that do have pointy edges
and don't always look like your traditional saucer
or egg or tic-tac.
In the 2003 Times,
a large group of Boeing contractors
were operating near one of the launch facilities
at Fandenberg Air Force Base
when they observed a very large,
100-yard-sided red square
approach the base from the ocean
and hover at low altitude over one of the launch facilities.
This object remained for about 45 seconds or so
before darting off over the mountains.
There was a similar event within 24 hours later in the evening.
This was a morning event.
I believe 8.45 in the morning.
Later in the evening, post-sunset,
there were reports of other sightings on base,
including some aggressive behaviors.
These objects were approaching some of the security guards
at rapid speeds before darting off.
The force fields interact with light.
When you see,
and you can see it on the tic-tac video,
the Navy pilots,
when you look at the video,
the first question,
you have to ask yourself
is when you're looking at the edges of the craft,
you have to ask yourself,
are you looking at just the force fields
that are interacting with light
that go away when the craft shuts down?
Or are you looking at the actual physical metal,
ceramic parts of the craft?
See?
And are you looking at a craft
that was designed to exceed the speed of light?
Or are you looking at a craft
that was just designed
for a specialized general kind of purpose
here on Earth?
Because remember,
the scout craft that you see,
like for the grays and the whites,
did not make the deep space crossing.
Only the deep space craft
make the deep space crossing.
What are the differences?
What's the main distinction?
The difference is...
The scout craft,
we use our bees to get around.
Yeah.
See, the deep space craft,
and I speak from direct observation,
they can all be individual,
like ships at sea,
or they can be general purpose.
Like, but one, for example,
looks like, well, you see how this house is.
One that I personally saw
was a little bit longer than this house,
a little bit wider than this house,
about half, again, as high as this house.
And it was all totally smooth all around, you know?
No protrusion or whatever.
It had the standard double hull,
and then it had another,
and the way,
this house has this room,
and then on the side,
it had another set of rooms.
So it had the double hull on the outside,
then it had a boundary area
where you'd store stuff on both sides,
and then it had the living area
where you had actual cabins,
the way you do on ships.
And then up at the front,
you had the cockpit and the control area
up on top,
and control lights up on top.
And then in the back,
you had the propulsion system.
And that was meant to put sand out to deep space
and head out for stars 100 light years away, okay?
I'm quite certain of that.
On the other hand,
see a saucer that you might have for your children
to take out to the play area, which I also saw.
It's not meant to go faster than light.
It's just meant to go like from Bishop, California
to Roswell, New Mexico in a half hour, you know?
And it could do it in 10 minutes,
but it's just meant to have a couple of teenagers
take charge,
put in three younger children,
say eight or 10,
and go out and play
and just go around places here on Earth.
So getting back to how you'd build the ideal.
When you build it,
if you build it for deep space,
and one that has,
like, that where you have, like, a ball inside
and then stuff outside,
like a cube or something,
you might ask,
is that really one craft?
Or is it the center ball is the real craft
and the outside is something like a car pulling a trailer?
You know,
see, you have to first ask,
who are they and what did they mean
to use that craft for?
You know, see.
Because they...
Mm-hmm.
because they don't just come here in a craft.
They build them while they're here.
Now, the Norwegians with 24 teeth
can only repair their craft when they get here,
at least in 1965.
One of the things they wanted to be able to do
was to work with the American government
and build craft here.
And that's, see, so whenever you see a craft,
whether it's a deep spacecraft or a scout craft
or whatever, you have to ask, what's it meant for?
If you really expect to do high speed,
like 50 light, well, like the scout craft
that the tall whites had that were ellipsoidal.
One time I asked, personally asked Range 4 Harry
if that craft could exceed the speed of light.
He was a very nice guy.
We were like brothers.
He was very adamant.
He said it could, but nobody, I'm gonna use my words,
in their right mind would ever take it that fast.
Once you got up to about 1% the speed of light,
you were covering distance so fast, in his words,
that if anything went wrong,
your friends couldn't find you.
And he didn't think it was made very well.
He pointed out that to repair it,
you had to sit the craft down somewhere like in the desert
and go outside and open it up to repair it.
But that the real deep spacecraft,
you could repair everything from the inside.
So the first thing that he thought
that a deep spacecraft had to have
was in addition to a double hull
and fiber optic windings in between those two hulls
to carry subatomic particles
that would generate the force fields
that you were working with,
that you had to have access,
from the inside of the craft, to repair them.
You had to be careful they didn't overheat.
If they overheated, you had to have,
the design had to apply,
you had to be able to repair that from the inside.
If you got in trouble,
you had to have emergency beacons
that used the force fields that travel faster than light
to send for help because those types of force fields
that you're using in the design,
like you could see it in the TikTok video.
If you're gonna control infrared rays
that are traveling at the speed of light,
you want to use a force field
that itself is traveling faster than the speed of light.
Otherwise,
you can't catch them and control them.
How does the,
how does,
you mentioned that the engine or the propulsion
is the only thing that the tall whites
didn't kind of fully give the humans
as far as the ability to sort of fly these UFOs.
Direct observation.
So, yeah.
So what do you think as far as how the,
how does, how do these engines work?
How are the, what's the power source?
And then obviously it's not chemical combustion.
So what's going on in the engine?
I'm quite certain that there's more subatomic particles,
more quarks than the six they know of.
There's at least two more sets.
But how, how do you get,
how do you figure that out when those two and when you.
Sorry, you have these like large Hadron colliders.
It's like super expensive to build.
It costs billions of dollars.
So how do you.
When you, when you design,
when you sit down to design a craft,
there's five subatomic particles.
There's five subatomic particles.
There's five subatomic particles that are virtually always used
because they're close to being stable
and easy to work with.
And what you need is to have ceramic fiber.
You need your, in your engine,
you have to produce those.
So you have, you don't have just one engine.
You have to have a way of producing all five of those.
And then what you have are ceramic fiber optic cables.
Ceramic fiber optic cables,
Ceramic fiber optics are 49.6% aluminum, 50.2% silicon dioxide.
That's the same as rocks.
And the remainder is the semiconductor, germanium, selenium, and so on,
that you use to coat those fibers with to create fiber optics.
And then you wind those into coils.
And those are, and whether you power up those coils or don't power up those coils,
that's how you control and propel your craft, okay?
And those five, and how you design those five depends
on what you want to do with your craft.
There's two more types of subatomic particles in that family that,
are more unstable, and are only occasionally used,
but not for craft that you would ever have children or a family on.
Because all of the extraterrestrials travel as families.
They would only be, you'd only find them on military craft.
And then there's two more, and so far we've talked about a total of nine, okay?
That are so unstable that you would never use,
and when you were designing your craft,
you'd only use them if you were designing a military weapon.
And when you say that number five, right, and the number seven,
that seems to ring a bell, doesn't it?
Because we're told that when Ike Eisenhower was president,
that there was a day that we're told publicly by ancient aliens and the U.S. press and so on,
that there was a day that somewhere,
the British guy said it was at Edwards,
other people said it was at Alamogordo,
but they say it was, there was a day somewhere where he was taken,
where they took him out, the day he was supposedly golfing at Palm Springs
and was taken to Edwards.
No cameras, no press,
and us sitting on the runway at Edwards were five,
five spacecraft with extraterrestrials by them,
and that they were shown to Ike Eisenhower.
Not one, except for the guy whose name is Charlo,
looked at that and said,
that makes perfect sense that they would do five,
because what they were showing him was the general features of how their airplane,
how their spacecraft were designed.
And you'd say, why five?
It's because they were showing that there were five different subatomic particles,
and that when they designed them,
they first said, I'm going to use this one for this purpose,
this one for the second one for another purpose, and so on.
And so they were showing them that they had five different purposes for that,
in the design, you see?
Okay, but those who, you know, who mean well,
think that they just arbitrarily showed five.
Another one is number three.
See, the fiber optics coils melt suddenly
at about somewhere between 1800 and 2200 Fahrenheit.
Not because they're made by aliens,
but because rocks melt between 1800 and 2200 degrees Fahrenheit.
And if they're 50.2% silicon dioxide and 49.6% aluminum,
that's what they're made of.
What they are is rocks.
And if they melt, and if the fiber optics melt,
as they did during the Roswell,
the two craft that crashed at Roswell,
as described in my book, The Valley of the Greys,
what you'll see, you would think, would be melted rocks.
I know, I know, UFO people try to pretend that there was one saucer,
and it was going fast, and it bounced,
and it hit the ground, and melted the rocks,
and then bounced up, and went on.
And my answer is, if you haven't, you know,
when was the last time you saw anything bounce against the rocks
in a Nevada, in a New Mexico desert?
I never have.
Once they hit the rocks, they break.
When the reason there were melted rocks there
is because there were two saucers,
and the fiber optics were overheating and melting.
And when they melted,
they melt like melted glass or lava,
and they have a big chunk that looks like lava,
and a big chunk falls, and then it hardens,
and hits the ground, and looks like a melted rock.
So when you see those reports that the geologist came,
and his son said, these are melted rocks,
and they left them behind,
and they say, we went out and picked up all the debris,
and we picked up this metal that,
that presumes its shape.
I said, those were cigarette wrappers.
Those were gum wrappers that did that.
What you passed over was the stuff you care about.
Okay.
I found a piece of metal, about a foot and a half
to two feet wide, and about two or three feet long.
Felt like you had nothing in your hands.
It wasn't any thicker than the foil out of a pack of cigarettes.
But the thing about that got me is that you couldn't even,
you couldn't bend it, you couldn't embed it,
even though the sledgehammer would bounce off of it.
So I knew that, I had never seen anything like that before,
and as of right, as of now, I don't know what it was.
So you're saying that Jesse Marcel,
that was just like the, the sort of memory metal,
that was just the, the kind of exhaust.
That could have come off from a kid's toy, okay.
Yeah, because, see what you have is what you,
after you've put in your melted, after you've put in your coils,
then you have to put it back in.
You have to protect them from the weather.
Now, when you protect them from the weather,
you're going to have to cover them with a thin metal sheet, okay.
But you're not going to be able to support the metal sheet
with an outside metal strap, okay.
You're not going to be able to protect the metal sheet
with an inside metal strap, because you can't have turbulence
in the force fields.
And you can, the metal is electromagnetic.
We'll screw it up with stray electromagnetism and so on.
And when you're designing it, you're going to start from square one,
and then three times a day, you're going to come up and say,
I don't want any turbulence in this force field.
I don't want these coils to overheat.
You're going to leave, if you're a gray designer,
and you're designing a coil,
and you're designing a craft for gray children,
then you're going to have, as per the Roswell Museum,
you're going to have something that is missing
from their display model.
On the underside, you're going to have a little doorway
that the operator of the craft can open anytime he wants
and let molten fiber optics fall out, okay,
because he's in desperate mode
to save his friends.
And then he can close the door and take off again.
And if he does, he may not be able to use all of his coils.
So if he's by himself, he's in deep trouble.
As in the craft over the plains of San Augustine in 1947,
he's by himself, and he's got big trouble.
But if he's got two craft beside him,
the fields from their craft
and the fields from his craft will join together,
as I've personally seen Range 4 Harry
do with the high-speed horse formation
to form a single larger craft
when the fields are present
and stabilize his craft.
And now the three together can fly off to someplace safe.
Okay?
Do you need to use specific metamaterials
for these, you know, very intense kind of, you know, environments
and, you know, a lot of electricity?
And, yeah, do you need to use specific materials for the craft?
Before you can know about the materials,
you have to know about the subatomic particles
because these ceramic fiber optics
are supposed to contain,
do what fiber optics do today,
what only they do it differently.
I've personally seen the fiber optics when,
as I describe in my book,
when I was in the sixth, the summer after my sixth,
between my fifth and sixth grade,
when Ray Palmer, the editor,
I believe that was his name,
editor of Flying Saucers magazine,
in a store in London, Wisconsin,
and his childhood friend who ran the store
came back from Roswell with a stretch about,
a yard long.
And it was, it was woven.
It wasn't a thin strip of metal.
It was like they took nylon fibers,
but it wasn't nylon, it was ceramic,
and wound it.
And then when you flowed, shined the flashlight through it,
the light would bend without being absorbed.
Now, you, but before you do it for the craft,
you first have to know about the particles
because you have to know how to build the fiber optics
before you can do anything else.
So Roswell, you mentioned the Roswell grays,
and you're talking about the Roswell craft.
The lore is that it made its way to Wright-Patterson,
Wright-Airfield at the time.
And you're saying it eventually made its way
to Area 51 or to the Nevada test range?
I don't know where it made its way to,
but I don't care because I've seen the real one
and I know what it looks like.
According to just, according to that-
Where'd you see it?
Did you see it in Nevada?
In Nevada.
I've seen a craft of that type many times.
On one, as I describe in my book
on the valleys of the grays,
on one cold and snowy night in the fall back in the 60s
when I damn near died in the fog,
and the scout craft with the young lady in it
and some of her friends,
accompanied by the deep space craft
and the teenage craft,
they had gone down to the bend in the road.
And she alone, she was just learning to run the craft,
so they didn't let her take it up in the air.
And before the fog moved in,
when I was walking down there,
I was on the side of a hill,
I was alone.
And she had brought the craft in
on the paved, on the gravel road.
She just had the control coils running.
And she had opened up the door on the side.
I was very reluctant to approach a craft
because I knew from experience that
they all have those fields surrounding them.
And that if you get too close,
it's like walking into the back of a jet engine
when the jet engine is running.
You gotta just stay and let them see you
and let them come as close as they want
or you'll get your ass burnt.
So I wasn't,
but she had powered down the outer coils.
So from her point of view,
there was nothing keeping me
from just walking the final distance
and stepping up into the craft
and saying hi
and meeting her and the others
who were on the craft.
I didn't realize at the time
that the teenager
who was the backup pilot,
he was a young grey.
They looked just like someone from Mongolia.
But the other three,
she and the other three,
were actually humans.
They were young Chinese people
that the greys had rescued,
not abducted,
but they had been orphaned
and the greys had reputed.
And the whole point was
that they were trying to return them
to human society.
But first you gotta find a human
who everybody trusts,
including the children.
And the human has to be somebody
who trusts them in return.
And the human they had figured
that they had chosen
had this last name Hall
and a first name Charlie.
Okay?
Charles, right?
And you say,
well, why didn't they tell me?
And they say,
well, that's why we picked him
because he'll figure it out
if we just give him time, right?
Why tell him early and scare him, right?
You know, that's why we picked him
because he's perfect at convergent,
divergent reasoning
and he'll figure it out.
And that's what they're doing,
waiting for me to come.
And what they had
was the very same craft
of the three that crashed at Roswell.
What they had
was the very same craft.
And in the back of that craft...
Do you think we know
how to fly these crafts now?
Do you think humans know how to fly them?
I'll finish this sentence
and then I'll answer it.
Yeah.
In the back of that craft
was a restroom.
In the back of all those people
are real physical biological entities.
They all have to eat,
they all have to breathe air,
drink water,
and they all have to periodically
go to the restroom.
And therefore,
every craft in the back
has a bathroom.
You see?
And therefore,
when you say,
like the crash at Kingman,
the lady that,
the young lady that survived,
the sheriff there said that
after she came out
and they were waiting for help to come,
what did she do?
In his own words,
he said she went back in the craft
and stayed in the back.
And one...
And the...
The UFO people say
it must be a shrine
where she was praying.
And of course,
I think that's really laughable
because having seen the craft,
there's no shrine back there.
What there is is a bathroom.
And if the craft...
And there's also food storage.
And so if the craft has crashed
and she's got to wait a while,
like every other biological entity,
they're going to fall back
on the bathroom.
You see?
There's no reason to fall back
on the control panels
because the craft isn't running.
That's why they crashed, see?
But the UFO people all have this thing,
well, there was a time they said
in all this craft
there must be a shrine in the back,
you know, where they go and pray.
And you say,
no, no, no, no.
I've seen the craft.
They're going,
that's a bathroom, right?
And I have a whole class of stories
in that vein.
No, no.
And so when I say my advantages
or I've been there and seen that,
I say the wreckage that was sitting
in the hangar at Roswell
that was recovered from Roswell,
when you say,
what was that like?
Well, that wreckage
had the bathroom on the other side.
And so that meant
for the part that blew in
was blowing in on the food storage,
you see?
And so when you went on the wreckage of that,
I would guess
that you would find on the other side
what remained of the restroom,
which might not be very much.
I'm saying when,
okay, but now an answer to,
what was your question
that you wanted me to answer?
I asked if humans,
can you mention that these,
there were these Chinese occupants
of the craft.
Do you think that humans can fly
these exotic, you know, ET crafts?
It's like everything else
if they're trained, okay?
It's like,
if they have an opportunity to learn,
if they have a trainer,
if they, yeah,
it's not something you can do naturally
for the same reason
that a Cessna airplane is a,
they tell me is a pretty simple airplane to fly.
I've actually flown one as co-pilot
for about 45 minutes,
but not by myself.
There was a trained pilot.
I was in the co-pilot seat
in a trained pilot seat.
The pilot was in the pilot seat.
And it was a nice night
and all I was doing
was flying straight and level
and saying,
yeah, I'm not moving anything.
Okay, if you call that flying,
well.
Does the training involve
the mind-matter connection?
There are rumors
that there are no control panels.
Do you sort of psychically connect
with the craft?
You don't do anything psychically.
Everything is electronics.
The electronics either
are adjusted
to tell what you're thinking
and therefore react
because you're thinking
or to not work at all.
It isn't the person
that has to change
their way of thinking.
It's the person
who's adjusting the electronics
has to adjust it.
It's unique for each human.
So how many of these tall whites
were out there with you,
if you had to guess or estimate?
It varied with how many ships
were in port.
See, the deep space ships
would arrive and would come
and go on schedule
the same way an airport is.
They liked to come and go
near the night of the full moon.
And on the night of the full moon,
the moon was
the moon and the earth
and the sun all form a line.
So behind the earth and its orbit
is a uniform gravitational field
and it's going away
from the incoming craft.
So if anything goes wrong,
they can back off
and the earth won't run into them.
It'll go away.
This is much different
than the Norwegians with 24 teeth
who want to come in
on the front side of the earth
because the Norwegians with 24 teeth
with less technology
must land
at any price,
even if the earth runs into them.
But the tall whites,
the deep spacecraft of the tall whites,
want to come in
on the night of the full moon.
The greys,
who have a base on the moon,
come and go at any time they want.
The tall whites,
the craft come on schedule
and they have different schedules.
Some are making a two-month schedule.
The longest schedule I saw
was craft that take five years
and those craft
with a five-year schedule,
I was told,
were coming directly
from their home planet.
Of course,
since all the craft travel
many times faster
than the speed of light,
I'm not sure
where their home planet was.
But if there were no craft in port,
then the number of tall whites
at the base
wasn't particularly large.
I'm not sure what the number was,
but it would be rare
to see as many as a hundred
out in the desert
if there were no ships
and deep spacecraft in port.
On the other hand,
the night that Pamela
was supposed to pass her test
to head up a technology transfer
for a tall white technology transfer team
by dressing up
and disguising themselves as,
and disguising herself
as a human woman
and the other tall white
by dressing up
and disguising himself
as a human man
specifically named Charlie Hall,
and she would specifically pretend
to be his wife
so they could go into places
like Livermore
and pretend to be humans
and talk to the scientists,
and I'm guessing...
Wait, explain what you just said.
In a minute.
The night she was going to pass that...
Are you saying
that you're a tall white?
No, I'm not a tall white.
I was born in Brooklyn, Wisconsin.
My parents all came from England.
Well, then,
but they mimicked you?
One of the tall whites
disguised themselves
as you and your wife
and then showed up
at Livermore Labs?
I'm guessing.
And how do you know?
Well, where did that come from?
I've never seen
any classified documents.
I'm guessing
only from my personal experience
talking with the tall whites.
They've told you
that they kind of used you
for inspiration
to infiltrate
or not infiltrate,
maybe that's too aggressive a word,
but to enter
American scientific programs.
I'm just totally guessing.
But the night she was...
To show them how to
not be afraid around humans
and to act easily
when in the presence of humans.
That was his whole MO
that he was supposed to be there.
So they...
Because they were
as terrified of us
as we might have been
terrified by them.
And it was...
That was what the program was.
But on that night,
on that night,
there were more
tall white scout craft
located up the valley
and on the eastern side
of Indian Springs Valley.
On what night?
The night that Pamela
was supposed to
pass her final exam.
The crowd that formed
of tall whites
and a few human generals
and bigwigs
on the eastern side
of the valley,
there were more
than I could count.
I stopped counting
at 35,
but I guessed
there were at least 70 there.
There were so many scout craft
and tall whites
that that whole side
of the valley
was white fluorescent,
white people,
scout craft.
It looked like
a county fair over there.
And all they were going to do
is watch her,
Pamela,
while the teacher and Pamela
over where the ammunition bunker was
at three and a half miles
was to watch her,
the teacher and Pamela
walk down
the paved pathway
or one lane road
from the ammunition bunker
on the east side
down to about
a half way
where there was a ridge
and then the teacher
would wait there
and then Pamela
with all of her technology
turned off.
Okay,
on totally trusting
to,
that I'm
a nice guy to be around,
okay,
otherwise totally helpless
against me if I'm not,
was supposed to
continue walking down the,
down the
pathway
until she got to the range boards
and then while I was working,
while I was,
had released the balloon
and I was tracking the balloon,
to just walk
over to me
disguised as a human,
she didn't have to be disguised
as a human lady,
just wearing her natural suit,
totally turned off
to just walk over to me
the way you and I are
and then while I was working,
walk around behind me
and turn her back to me,
proving that she trusted me
just like the scene
from The Man Called Horse
where the,
where the guy,
where the Indian chief does that
to horse,
turn her off,
turn her on
and talk to me
with her back turned towards me,
totally turned off
her everything
and then walk around
to the other side
with everybody watching
and then walk around
and say it's been so nice
to meet you Charlie
and then go on
and then,
then she could then leave
then,
and her husband,
the guy pretending to be me
as her husband
would then have to do it next,
okay,
on that night,
on that night
she failed the test
on that night she panicked
and got about,
well she didn't even get down
to the quarter mile limit
when she panicked
and was afraid that I was a,
truly an ugly monster
that she couldn't trust
and ran off
but there came a night
when she had to do that
and that's described in my book.
What do you,
what do you think
the Tallwhites want with humanity?
Do you think they have goals for us
or do you think they're
just trying to engage
in diplomatic relations?
Well,
they came here in the middle
of the last ice age
because
we,
for the same reason
that we have a base on Guam.
The sun and the solar system
exists in a,
the middle
of a huge void in space.
The next closest star,
Alpha Centauri
or Proxima Centauri
is almost four light years away.
Most stars
or many stars
have another star
within two light weeks.
Okay,
it's not all unusual
for many stars to be
not more than a light year apart.
For the,
if you're going to cross
that big void in space
as you're conducting
interstellar commerce
for your own good,
then it's nice to have a place
in the middle
because that void
is there for something like
eight or ten light years across.
Or six or eight,
a big long line there.
It's nice to have a place
in the middle
where you can stop
and get food and water,
go outside your spacecraft
and repair it,
where you can stop and rest
and,
but also get minerals
or other things
that you might need.
So it's a pit stop.
It's a pit stop.
Interesting.
And,
and of course the reason
that there are many
of their spacecraft
doing that is because
there's only,
it is for the same reason
that there are many
Air Force planes
that stop at Guam
because location,
location,
location.
What do you make of?
Now, if you're there,
it's a big help
if you have some locals
who grow some food for you,
they're plant eaters,
the toloites,
as the grays are,
and do the work of harvesting
and hand you the food.
What do you make of rumors
that,
you know,
there's a lot of stories
that,
like Eisenhower,
you know,
meeting possibly,
Palm Springs 1954,
this,
this treaty,
you know,
you say five,
five crafts showed up.
There's another story,
called,
you know,
Holman Air Force Base,
where there's a landing
and there's a possible
interaction between,
you know,
some generals on the base
and these,
these tall beings,
but they seem to actually
have like almost
pharaonic Egyptian headdress.
And,
this was,
this video,
I think,
was promised at one point
to Rod Serling
and Bob Emmenager
who made UFOs
past,
present,
and future.
And,
the video never came.
But,
I've spoken to,
you know,
some pretty interesting people
in the UFO whistleblower world
who,
do stand by that account,
that,
that was like a real meeting.
Do you,
do you think that that happened?
And was it,
was it tall,
was it a tall white
that came out of the craft
at Holman Air Force Base?
Well,
I'll maintain my policy
of never commenting
on other people's stories.
And,
and the reason,
the reason is because,
my books are based totally
on my own experience.
Yep.
And,
and it's not based
on anything I've read
or any,
they're not based
on any,
any classified material.
I was never part
of any project.
They're based
on what,
when you say,
what was life
for me?
And,
and,
and what I'm trying
to do in my books,
one of the major things
I'm trying to do
in my books
is I'm trying
to tell my grandkids
how it was for me.
And I'm trying
to point out to them
that when you're personally dealing
with the extraterrestrials,
you feel differently
than when you're personally dealing
with your guardian angels.
Your guardian angels
are like,
are like brothers
who love you.
There's never any fear
with this,
the sensation
that your guardian angels
are there with you.
And if,
because each of us,
I believe,
has two guardian angels,
at least,
who are always with us
and have nothing else to do
but keep track
of each one of us.
And,
and,
and I get so frustrated
when I see so many humans
who mean well
trying to confuse
guardian angels
and what God
and love
and the guardian angels
are doing
with what
the biological entities
who are extraterrestrials
are doing.
And so,
and that's what I'm trying
to do in my book.
I'm not trying to,
I don't care
what the government
wants to classify.
That's fine with me
if they want to classify
the recipe
for Hershey candy bars
and say,
you know,
you can have one, Charlie,
but don't tell anybody.
Do you,
do you miss,
do you miss the Tallwhites?
Do you feel an emotional affection
towards them?
You said that you
and Range 4 Harry
were like brothers.
Uh,
do you ever think,
hey,
maybe I could contact
Range 4 Harry
or go back
and speak to him,
go back to the,
to the range,
to Nellis?
Well,
uh,
if I,
let's say,
if I were out
in the desert,
let's say out by Dale
here in New Mexico,
which is one
of the Tallwhite playgrounds,
let's say if,
if I ever were out there
and,
and let's say
I happened to see them,
if I were to just say,
well,
I just wanted to,
you know,
monkey around
and see you
or,
you know,
whatever,
well,
that,
they might say,
well,
now you've seen us
and so go on
about their business.
See,
they're very goal-oriented
even though
they like it.
They like us.
And it's not that
they're being rude.
It's because,
remember,
the teacher
in 1965
who had been born
when George Washington
was born,
when she was playing
with,
when she was over
at range two
that Sunday
with her daughter,
who she called
the butterfly
and the little
white girl
that she wanted
to be friends
with her little,
with her daughter
and,
because she,
the little girls
could be friends.
She was standing there
on the side
in a very,
now,
they were playing
on the skip-bomb area
and the two,
the two boys
were playing
also.
She was standing
a little ways away
from them
on the higher ground,
slightly higher ground.
She was very nostalgic
remembering
her childhood
where she played
on the same piece
of ground
with a little
Native American girl
who,
who was equivalent
to her age,
five years old
at the time.
But her memories
of that
little
Indian,
Native American girl
that was her
very best friend
at the time,
in the time,
because they lived
ten times longer
than we do,
in the time
that passed
while she went
from
equivalently being,
say,
in the fourth grade
to the seventh grade,
for us,
those are
different
things.
And,
and,
So,
yeah,
that is
what we're
researching
together.
I mean,
we do have
some
forgiveness
for people
in the place
of RPD sometimes,
and our
confrontations
Deniations
and our
darkness
are
all
catches
things
simultaneously.
This is
something
we don't
have
without
a
person's
automatically
sense
from their point of view, gee, I'm 80 years old right now.
You know, I'll be dead in what for them is
the blink of an eye.
I don't know, even if I live to be 100,
I'll, you know, it's just two more,
I only have two more years to live.
So from their point of view,
if I say we're out there at my age,
they would, they might,
I mean, they're friends,
but you have to remember that socializing
and being friends for them with humans
is a little bit like us being friends
and socializing with, say, a dog in its old age
that we may not have seen for five or 10 years.
There's a guy at NASA who has a deep interest
in these sorts of things.
Experiencers, his name is Timothy Taylor.
Have you heard of him by any chance?
Did you say Timothy Taylor?
Yeah.
Oh, he's a good friend of ours.
Oh, so you know Timothy Taylor?
Mm-hmm.
Tim Taylor.
This is one of those characters where,
well, if you know, you know,
but if you don't, there's probably a reason
why the mood shifted here, folks.
Tim Taylor was a NASA engineer
who became a biotech entrepreneur.
And according to Diana Pasulka's book,
American Cosmic, where he appeared under the pseudonym
Tyler Dee, has remained actively involved
in launch operations for NASA up until today.
Pasulka paints Taylor as an enigmatic figure
who led her and Stanford microbiologist Gary Nolan
to a UFO crash site in New Mexico.
By many, he's considered a gatekeeper,
well-connected with access to crash retrieval secrets,
as well as personally receiving
what he termed downloads of information
from otherworldly sources.
He claimed these downloads were facilitated
by protocols he engaged in,
protocols that allowed him to communicate
with non-human intelligences.
In Pasulka's book, Taylor undergoes a profound conversion
in the Vatican archives, blending technology
and the phenomenon in what became a personal revelation.
And then he decided to convert.
But also what happens is he changes his idea
of what these things are that he's feeling
he's getting signals from.
Because we were studying saints
who had these experiences,
and he was thinking that they're more in line
with what they were, you know, experiencing, too.
And outside of her account,
super experiencer Chris Bledsoe's memoir
openly names Taylor as a NASA insider
who befriended him after his encounters.
Sometimes Taylor would bring other scientists or officials
to witness Bledsoe's experiences.
I, myself, was briefly in contact with Taylor,
and I'm not sure what to make of him.
And even though
shocked that his name came up in this conversation. I wasn't necessarily surprised. The deeper cut on
Tim Taylor is that he himself is some sort of time traveler, part of a secret program adjusting
timelines. This doesn't come from me. Perhaps my favorite figure, aerospace engineer and
anti-gravity inventor Thomas Townsend Brown, is connected with Tim Taylor. This is where the story
gets weird. Thomas Townsend Brown was obsessed with anti-gravity, but gravity and time have a
tight relationship in general relativity. This is just standard physics. So the subplot of his
great biography by Paul Shatskin, The Man Who Mastered Gravity, is that Townsend Brown was
obsessed with time travel. He would talk about it constantly with his friends and family. Apparently,
Tim Taylor told Ryan Bledsoe, Chris Bledsoe's son, that he was part of a secret group in Nassau in
the Bahamas that dealt with time travel. I would dismiss this out of hand entirely, but there
are some even more interesting connections between Townsend Brown and Tim Taylor. There's an Amazon
review that Townsend Brown's daughter wrote on Tim Taylor's biography, Launch Fever. In that
biography, Tim Taylor talks about his time traveling back and forth to the Bahamas. He spent a lot of
time in Nassau. Townsend Brown also spent a ton of time in Nassau. In fact, his biographer, Paul
Shatskin, even coined a term for a secret group that used to meet there. It was called the Nassau
Group, and it included the elite of the Nassau group. The Nassau Group is a group of people who
lead the elite, industrialists like Eldridge Reeves Johnson, and even the inspiration for James Bond
and Churchill's super spy, William Stevenson, who helped form the CIA. So maybe Tim and Townsend are
part of a secret time travel group. Who knows? But it is interesting that Taylor seems to
consistently pop up around very important experiencers in the United States. Now back
to our conversation. How did you guys originally meet Tim Taylor? He's sort of this very interesting
figure.
You know, he works with Nassau, and he's very interested.
He came here because he found out about Charles. And that was when his daughter, the one who had
the baby, was like, what was she, maybe in fifth grade when they came the first time?
Yeah, we...
Why do you think he became interested in your story?
My wife can answer all the questions.
Because he realized that as far as...
Charles was...
The real article was legitimate.
And as I say, it's really
concerned me because I've tried to
email other people. Because he brought other people
to meet us
and visit with us.
One of the guys cooked right here in my kitchen.
So I tried to contact those people because I had
emails for them.
and I never got a response about what happened to him.
Who did he bring?
Let me see.
King, David King, wasn't that his name?
And what was the doctor that was, I think I still have the emails,
but he brought lots of people here and, oh, brought them to Las Vegas.
Kit Green, Dr. Kit Green, maybe, no?
We were at Green's house, I believe.
He flew us to Atlanta and had us meet the, oh, what was their last name?
No, I can't remember.
I know who you mean, honey, but I don't remember their last name either.
We met all his friends.
They had a whole house full of people and entertained us.
Interesting.
What did you get the sense, did they just want to learn or did they,
what do you think?
They were just big fans, but because he introduced them to us.
What did you get the sense of, like, his job at NASA?
Do you know what he does?
He said that he was no longer involved, that he went into business for himself
and he would, oh, that's the interesting story.
He'd been all over to the various Air Force bases, et cetera,
but he'd never been to Creech before.
And so when he came back from Creech the first time,
he said he thought that Charles underplayed the strangeness that was going on there.
He said they were there for a ribbon-cutting ceremony
and he was standing right next to a friend of his.
Oh, there were no lower-ranking people, just all officers.
And he said to the guy,
do you mind if I just drive up the road, you know, a mile or two?
I won't get out of the car.
And the guy said, oh, that would be a very bad idea.
And then just that quickly he said, I'm so glad you could make it for this.
You know, like, I didn't say what I just said.
And, yeah, so he was really even more impressed with Charles.
And he had a very good account after he finally got the chance to visit Creech for the first time.
Did he ever say where his interest in ETs came from?
I don't remember that he said that, no.
There were many things.
We never talked about his work or things of that nature.
And we also never talked about projects that he was associated with or anything like that.
Did he ever ask you about your Hall photon?
I'm sure we talked about it.
He was interested actually in buying a house and moving out here.
He seems to pop in when experiencers have anomalous experiences.
We never had any trouble getting in touch with him.
And as I say, the last contact we had was just when he said, you know,
he was looking forward to being a grandfather.
And that was it.
He just disappeared.
We never heard from him since.
I've heard that from numerous people.
He did that.
I mean, I had very intermittent correspondence with him, but he dropped off on me, Chris Bledsoe, a bunch of other people.
It's just that ours went on for so many years.
Yeah.
You said 15 years?
I think so, yeah.
Wow.
It's so strange that he would just not contact you after 15 years, though.
Yeah.
I mean, we shared a lot of really personal things.
And, you know, of course, he converted to Catholicism.
Yeah.
Recently in, what, in 2015, 16-ish?
Something like that.
During his trip to the Vatican.
Yeah.
And he'd been to Rome several times after that.
So, yeah.
Do you think when he went to the Vatican archives, he experienced anything around the E.T. topic?
Any confirmation of that?
I have no idea.
No idea.
We put, I think we Xeroxed it and put it in book four, maybe.
Wow.
Could we see that?
I'd love to see the thank you note.
That'd be amazing.
Oh, it's in book four.
Okay.
That's awesome.
Do you believe that Timothy Taylor has ever met an extraterrestrial?
He certainly didn't say anything about meeting one.
Or has he shared any personal sightings that he's ever had?
No, but maybe the fact that he disappeared, maybe he went off with them.
I don't know.
One night I was out in range three and a group of new arrivals.
It was after the full moon, a week or so.
And as usual, a group of the guards, the permanently assigned tall white guards at the base up at the north end of Indian Springs Valley,
brought down, they were using the tourist model scout craft,
which had...
They had seating for like two dozen and they brought them down to the range three area so they could see me the first human that any of those tall whites had ever seen.
And while I was there, they came in too close.
I expect them, being new people, to stop at least at a quarter mile, which was more common, but they kept coming in because they were assured that I was a nice guy until they were as close as...
Well, this was new.
The guard was in position.
This was when I was still new and still not completely at ease being around them.
And since the new people are armed too, that meant that, you know, I was somewhat intimidated.
And there was an older lady or a middle-aged lady.
And I was at my theodolite stand.
I was tracking the balloon.
And so I said, well, so I just turned to him and I said,
I looked at him and I just said, I'm feeling a little scared.
And, you know, so I'm just going to put my stuff here and I'm going to go into base and you guys can stay and look around and do whatever you want and have fun.
And then I backed away and I went walking, not running, key point, walking to my truck that was parked some distance away on the other side of my, the generator shack.
And as I was walking, this middle-aged lady said to the guard,
she was kind of surprised.
She said, we didn't do anything wrong.
Did we?
I mean, you know, we didn't and, and the, you know, what's he like?
And the guard proceeded to tell the group what they thought I was like.
The guard said, and I quote, well, he seems to talk more than most humans and he seems to eat a lot more than most humans and us.
But, you know, you don't worry if you say.
He scares a lot more easily than most humans.
But see, he's different.
He just goes in and talks and eats and then he comes right back out.
The others, once we find them would never come back and might not eat again for a couple of days.
And they were all laughing.
So just wait here.
He'll be back out after lunch.
Just give him time to eat and talk to some of the other guys.
He'll be right back.
Wow.
And that's what they thought of me.
That encapsulates how I wasn't braver than the other guys.
I scared easier, but just let me eat and talk for a while.
I'll get over it.
Well, that encapsulates, I think you and how special you are because it, it shows in the, um, documentary that Emil made as well, where like, initially you are scared and you don't know what to do.
And I think most people would have a reflexive allergic reaction and kind of run away.
And your reaction is just this kind of, I know 41 men that would agree with you.
Yeah.
If, if the, not all of them are still alive.
Right.
Oh, oh, interesting.
So 41 men who were had nervous break.
Downs were sent out before me and came back, came back compromised, compromised, meaning mentally unstable.
Some of them, but some of them just wouldn't go out there again.
Just, well, the one, the guy before me had deserted, but the one I remember, the one I always felt sorry, it's the one I described in my book.
He was the one that was out at range for one night and when they first sent him out there and the tall whites came.
In the, in, I'll use my words, not his, the tall whites came in the high speed horse formation and they came from the Northwest mountains that when you're in Indian Springs amount to the North and Northwest, it came down and they were coming across the dry lake bed at range four.
And they were very close to where, and he was, he was at the weather station at range four and he couldn't believe they were real because they were floating.
And.
And when he, so he went out there and surprised him and he got too close to him because they still had their suits powered up and they were still in the tall white for in the high, in the floating, in the high speed horse formation and he got too close to him and the suits, which put out radioactive particles and you could see them.
They see when they were turned up high enough, they would sparkle.
You could see the alpha particles and the beta particles and stumbling out and the other particles.
You could actually see the decay chains coming off the suits and the suit and his shoulder almost touched one of the shoes and I saw his x-rays and pictures at the, when I was at the Nellis base hospital and, and it, in the, it, the doctor himself said it, it looked like the wounds from the victims of the Hiroshima blast and it looked like his whole show, the meat, the family, everything.
Yeah.
Had been cooked off.
Wow.
Okay.
Yeah.
Had, had been cooked off.
You know, the bone was exploited and he just barely made it back to base alive.
Did you ever, did you ever experience any radiation damage due to interactions with them or?
No, not that I'm aware of.
And part of the reason was because, part of the reason was because you could see the, the fluorescent, if they had their suits turned up high enough, you could see the radioactive particles.
And of course I recognized them immediately as radioactive decay particles because in those days in the early 19, that was, it was in 1965, we'll see in the early 1950s, you could still get radium paint and put it on your watch or your toys.
And if you had a magnifying glass and you went into a very dark room and waited like 45 or 50 minutes for your eyes to perfectly adjust to the darkness, you could still get radium paint and put it on your watch or your toys.
darkness and used a magnifying glass, you could actually see the subatomic particles come off
the radium paint, the alpha particles, the beta particles, the gamma rays. And see, so when I saw
those coming off the suits of the tall whites out in the desert, I knew perfectly well what they
were. I was surprised by how big the tracks were and how far they carried. When it came off from
radium paint, the tracks would be coming off just a short distance like that. When you saw them out
in the desert, they would be coming off distances like that there. So those suits had a tremendous
power. Charles, this has been an absolute honor. I appreciate your time, man.